foreign
I was looking through some old photo
albums recently and seeing images of my
past self made me realize that it is
only fairly recently that I felt at
peace in regards to having a healthy
relationship with my body and
nourishment in general
as you may know I've made videos in the
past about recovering from an eating
disorder
but a long story short my problem was
merely a symptom of a deeper issue
and for me it was a fear of the
responsibilities of adulthood a failure
in general and seeking a sense of
control living with a heart that was too
ready to take on burdens
[Music]
it took me seven years to feel fully and
completely recovered from my disorder
that is a very long time
and I wanted to say that number because
I think that time taught me something I
didn't expect
when it comes to improving Our Lives
reaching our goals and dreams putting an
immediate deadline for achieving them
can risk sabotaging the entire Journey
[Music]
foreign
there are many cases when we simply must
accept that we're complex and deserve to
discover equally complex answers trying
to skip to the end result makes it
meaningless and the truths we need to
uncover are found over the course of
years and the wisdom gained simply
through being alive
[Music]
thank you
I was not unhappy and miserable for
those seven years to be clear I was not
simply putting my life on hold because
when I started the road to recovery and
facing the other mental issues I had to
address I was choosing to actually start
living to see things out and when you
choose to do that it doesn't mean you're
ready to be perfect or live the ideal
version of your life or not make
mistakes it doesn't mean choosing to be
happy while sweeping those other
uncomfortable emotions under the rug
if anything I started that road to
recovery when I started to let myself
feel deeply feel the pain I was holding
the fears I had and consequently
discover that deep desire to be alive
even though that wish was hidden away
under many layers of Lies I had told
myself
the lie that things don't change the lie
that I don't deserve help
we all have limitations but there is
always at least something we can do to
make tomorrow a bit better even if it's
a very small change
at least I needed to believe that to
start moving forward this is what worked
for me and you must discover what works
for you
isn't that rather exciting
[Music]
seven years of ups and downs joy and
sadness and building the foundation for
a strength in my core that I could have
never imagined
if I met my past self I know she would
be so proud and amazed that I waited out
the storm and became something so
beautiful in the process that I would
never dare believe that the world would
be better without me anymore
[Music]
foreign
speaking from my heart to all of you
because if you cannot relate to this
story there's likely someone in your
life who can
and they need your love and
understanding it's what humans do best
in my opinion to love and we can always
use more of it in this world
[Music]
I remember I was once at a house party
when I was quite young and I was having
a really hard time you know that year I
remember I was in university and very
affected by the environment I was just
learning how to be an adult and like for
so many adults at that age I was just
having a hard time I was feeling quite
overwhelmed and nervous my introvert
itself was just screaming for help and
so I remember I went out to the porch
just to get a breath of fresh air there
was a young man there just doing I think
pretty much the same thing I remember we
chatted just a little bit
and um he asked me if I was okay because
I think he could tell in my face that I
was having a hard time and I didn't
really want to be there
and I was in a moment of vulnerability
and and I told him no you know I haven't
been doing okay for a while to my
surprise he just nodded and he offered
to give me a hug and
um said I totally get it the weight of
human consciousness is just a lot
sometimes and that's okay and I'm sure
it'll get better firstly I'm still
amazed to hear such a beautiful words of
wisdom from someone so young in
University at a house party probably
quite inebriated somehow those words
have stayed with me and I have repeated
them to other people you know when
they're having a hard time and I think
something about acknowledging that it's
just sometimes hard to be human you know
hard to have so much knowledge of the
things going on in this world caring
deeply about suffering wanting the world
to be a better place you know not
knowing how to make it better not
knowing how to be the best version of
yourself you know all these thoughts and
questions you know rolling about your
head can just be hard sometimes and
that's okay recently I've been hearing a
lot of that saying of you survived all
your worst days be proud of yourself and
I think that that's so sweet and simple
but true you know think of all the low
points that you have gotten to in your
life and you have gotten through them if
you're watching this video so I I think
that's something really important to
acknowledge and be proud of my husband
for example is a very gentle kind person
that always makes me feel very safe and
I know that I would appreciate that of
him no matter what my life experiences
are but looking back at the abusive
relationships I experienced I do value
him in such an incredible way when I
chose to start that road of recovery I
wasn't just choosing from day one you
know to figure things out and
immediately you know change everything
about my lifestyle and all my decisions
and the reason that it took me so long
to fully recover from the disorder I was
facing was because I was not ready to
truly and completely face every single
fear
anxiety and issue that I had that
process took years of gaining courage to
unpack those layers but every day I
chose to live and to try to enjoy life a
little more to be a little better
version of myself to let go of one more
little part of that self-medicating
behavior that was unhelpful to me but I
think for that very same reason is why
the end result has been so lasting and
so welcome it is amazing to look back
and see what you thought was just
impossible has become possible and you
also learn to embrace a life of
discomfort you know a life of ups and
downs a life of the full spectrum of
human emotions of
tears of laughter of vulnerability and
that means signing up for a life of
potential hurt and you know truly and
deeply feeling all those feelings not
all of them which are very comfortable
but at the end of the day you do know
that you have been allowing yourself to
feel and deeply feel and that that's
such a beautiful such a human and such a
I think recipe for lasting fulfillment
face those fears little by little and
just make take those baby steps of
progress It's amazing over the course of
years how far you can get on a far more
light-hearted note I did want to share
that I recently went to a really fun
type Affair it's called a bartering Fair
it's a little bit like a flea market but
instead of bringing money you can bring
money and buy things but you are also
encouraged to bring items and trade
whenever you can walk into a space and
twenty dollars will get you so many
random antique interesting items then I
am very happy I hope that this inspires
you to go antique shopping or thrift
store shopping and looking at what all
these beautiful second-hand shops have
to offer it is such a sustainable and
just wonderful I think way to bring
items into your home that have a story
that being said I am of course sending
my love I hope you have a absolutely
wonderful week and I will see you very
soon do take care of yourself
goodbye
[Music]